(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-17T05:37:33.051543",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
パレ、パレ、パレ！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
Shine bright!
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal!
パレ、パレ、パレ！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探すにゆく
Let's go search!
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start over!
パレ、パレ、パレ！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
Shine bright!
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal!
パレ、パレ、パレ！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探すにゆく
Let's go search!
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start over!
ただ 独り言を紡いだ
I just spun monologues to myself.
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I just ran because I wanted it to begin.
やさしすぎる想いも もっと
Even feelings that are too tender, even more
じっと繋ぎとめた手を伸ばした
I reached out the hand I tightly held onto
想いかけず結びあった
Unexpectedly bound together
ほら 今 僕らはひとつになった
Look, now we have become one
パレ パレ パレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining brightly
今宵さまよう瞳も 連れておいで
Bring your wandering eyes along tonight
立て夢はね 飛び立てるさ
Stand up, dreams take wing, you can soar
ささやかな祈りは 光
A modest prayer is light
終わりなき兆し 君を見つけたこと
Endless signs, finding you
胸を張れるよ ここから ここから
I can hold my head high, from here, from here
アワープライ パレ パレ
Our bright parade, parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
Still unsure feelings
歌おう
Let's sing them
恥ずかしかなんてないよ
There's nothing to be embarrassed about
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can solve
いつか また逢える おまじない
A spell to meet again someday
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that started at zero that day
数え切れない 言葉の葉
Countless leaves of words
ほら 今 僕らはひとつだよ
Look, now we are one
パレ パレ パレ 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, it's so beautiful
許し合える 刹那 夜はきらめく
Moments of forgiveness, the night sparkles
雨 晴れ カレイド またとない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope, a sky like no other
相応しい旅路とは 君と歩くことさ
A fitting journey is walking with you
君と歩くことなんだ
It's walking by your side
だから 今は聞けよ
So listen now
お帰りって叫ぶよ
I'll shout welcome home
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that only natural?
パレ パレ パレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining brightly
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
What fills the darkness is you, it's me
パレ パレ パレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining brightly
今宵さまよう瞳も 連れておいで
Bring your wandering eyes along tonight
立て夢はね 飛び立てるさ
Stand up, dreams take wing, you can soar
ささやかな祈りは 光
A modest prayer is light
終わりなき兆し 君と飛び込んでゆく
Endless signs, diving in with you
ここから ここから アワープライ パレ パレ
From here, from here, our bright parade, parade!
I'm ready ハート コネクト 約束の時間
I'm ready, heart connect, time for our promise
今日も元気に… あてんしょんぷりーず
Energetic today too... Attention please!
あてんしょんぷりーず！
Attention please!
凛々しく・かしこく・エリートらしく
Dignified, smart, like a true elite
みんなのアイドルは今日も今日とてKAWAII
Everyone's idol is cute today too
よなよなオンステージ
Night after night, on stage
アツい視線はスポットライトですありがとね
Your passionate gaze is the spotlight, thank you
ウェルカム スタンバイOK 宣誓 ごあいさつ
Welcome, standby OK, vow and greetings
本日ここに開花宣言！
Full bloom declaration right here today!
イッツ ショータイム あっちゅあっちゅぱーりーないっ
It's showtime, hot, hot party night
飛びきりの時間 夢中にさせてあげるから
A special time, I'll make you enchanted
うれしたのしや 歌い明かそうよ 朝が来るまで
Joyful and fun, let's sing until morning comes
あてんしょんぷりーず
Attention please!
i'm ready
ハートコネクト 約束の時間
Heart connect, the appointed time
今日も元気に行こう…
Full of energy today as well...
あてんしょんぷりーず♪
Attention Please! ♪
凛々しく・かしく・エリートらしく
Dignified, smart, and like an elite,
みんなのアイドルは今日も今日てkawaii
everyone's idol is kawaii today as well.
よなよな(よなよな)
Every night (every night)
オンステージ(オンステージ)
on stage (on stage).
アツい視線はスポットライトで
Your passionate gaze is the spotlight,
ありがとね
thank you!
ウェルカム スタンドバイOK
Welcome, standby OK,
宣誓 ごあいさつ
oath and greeting.
本日 ここに開花宣言！
Today, a declaration of blooming right here!
イッツ ショータイム
It's showtime!
あっちゅ あっちゅ ぱーりーないっ とびきり の 時間
Attchu attchu party night, an extraordinary time,
夢中 に させ て あげる から
I'll make you completely enchanted!
うれし たのし 歌い 明かそうよ
Let's joyfully sing the night away
朝が来る まで
Until the morning comes,
あて ん しょん ぷりー ず ♪
Attention Please! ♪
泣い てる 姿 は 見せ たく ない
I don't want to show you the side of me crying.
努力 も ヨユウ だ よ だって みんな の おかげ
Effort is a breeze, because of everyone.
キラキラ 笑顔 が 思い出す たび 毎日 エール くれる から
Sparkling smiles, every day you give me cheers
サンキュー 今日 は その こと 伝え に 来 た よ
Thank you, I came to tell you that today.
だから たくさん いい 表情 しよっ！
So let's make lots of great expressions!
まばたき 注意
Blink and you'll miss it,
しっかり 焼き付ける ね
I'll burn it into your eyes firmly.
キミとハートコネクト
Heart connect with you,
おわりたくないよ
I don't want it to end.
賛成 の ひトー？ アンコール！
Anyone in favor? Encore!
あっちゅ あっちゅ ぱーりーないっ とびきり の 時間
Attchu attchu party night, an extraordinary time,
とっくにクセになってるはず
It should already be a habit by now.
うれしたのし 歌い明かそうよ
Let's joyfully sing the night away
朝が来るまで
Until the morning comes,
あてんしょんぷりーず♪
Attention Please! ♪
盛り上がろうね Theぱーりーないっ♪
Let's get hyped, the party night ♪
はーい、ということでにゃっはろー！
Hi, everyone! Hello!
エリートみこのさくらみこです！
It's hololive's Sakura Miko!
今日は5周年記念ライブ！
Today is my 5th anniversary live!
アイドルよ、あてんしょんぷりーずに来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you for coming to Attention Please!
で、えーと、ハッシュタグはこちら！
And now, the hashtag is right here.
こちらでたくさんスクショして、たくさんツイートしてね、よろしくお願いします！
Please take lots of screenshots and post them!
えー、ということで、ここからはゲストパートやっていきたいと思います！
And from here, we're going to do a guest part!
あ、そういえば、あ、これ、これ見てこれ、かわいい！
Oh, wait, let's look at this—isn't it cute?
これね、作ってもらいましたたい焼き、でっけー！
They made this taiyaki for me!
ということで、ここからはもりだくさんのゲストパート！
So from here, it's the guest part with lots of guests,
そして、お披露目もあるので、最後まで見てねー！
and also some exciting announcements, so watch till the end!
カレンダーより早く
Earlier than the calendar,
シャツの袖口まくって
I'm already rolling up my sleeves.
太陽が近づく気配
Feels like the sun is coming close,
僕の腕から衣替え
so I'm changing clothes for the season.
青い海 波打ち際で 君と会いたい
Within the blue sea, near the beach, I want to meet you,
素足の水しぶき
splashing water barefooted.
ポニーテール(揺らしながら) 風の中
Your ponytail (is swinging) in the wind,
君が走る(僕が走る) 砂の上
you're running (I'm running) on the sand.
ポニーテール(揺らしながら) 振り向いた
Your ponytail (is swinging) when you turn your head,
君の笑顔 僕の夏が始まる
my summer is starting with your smile.
教室に陽が射して
The classroom is basking in the sun,
夢の気温が上がった
temperature is rising for daydreams.
斜め前の君見てると
Looking at you in front of me
胸が苦しくなってくる
makes my chest painful.
好きなんて 言えやしないよ
It's impossible to say that I like you,
後ろ姿に 気持ちをつぶやく
so I murmur my feelings to your back figure.
ポニーテール(切なくなる) 夢の中
Your ponytail (stings my heart) just in my dream,
君のすべて(僕のすべて) 一人占め
whole of you (all of me) wish to possess it.
ポニーテール(切なくなる) 片想い
Your ponytail (stings my heart) with unrequited feeling,
瞳と瞳合わせれば 今はただの友達
when our eyes meet I know we're just friends.
東ねた長い髪 水玉のシュシュ
Your long hair is bundled in a polkadot scrunchie,
恋の尻尾は 捕まえられない
I cannot catch that tail of love.
触れたら消えていく 幻
If I touch it, this illusion will disappear.
ポニーテール(ほどかないで) 変わりなく
Your ponytail (don't untie it) keep it like usual,
君は君で(僕は僕で) 走るだけ
you are you (I am me) and we're just running.
はしゃいでいる 君は少女のままでタ
You are just acting like a girl forever.
ララララララ…
LaLaLaLaLaLa...
ララララ…
LaLaLaLa...
カレンダーより早くシャツの袖口まくって
Earlier than the calendar, I'm rolling up my sleeves
太陽が近づく気配 僕の腕から衣替え
Feels like the sun is getting closer, changing clothes from my arms
青い海 波打ち際で 君に会いたい 素足の水しぶき
Near the blue sea, by the crashing waves, I want to meet you, barefoot water splashes
ポニーテール 揺らしながら
Your ponytail swinging
風の中 君が走る 砂の上
in the wind, you're running on the sand
ポニーテール 振り向いた
Your ponytail when you turn around
君の笑顔 僕の夏が始まる
Your smile, my summer begins
教室に陽が射して 夢の気温が上がった
Sunlight streams into the classroom, raising the temperature of dreams
斜め前の君見てると 胸が苦しくなってくる
Looking at you diagonally in front of me makes my chest ache
好きなんて言えやしないよ 後ろ姿に気持ちをつぶやく
I can't say I like you, so I whisper my feelings to your back
ポニーテール 切なくなる
Your ponytail, it breaks my heart
夢の中 君のすべて 僕のすべて 一人占め
In my dream, all of you, all of me, all to myself
ポニーテール 片想い
Your ponytail, unrequited love
瞳と瞳合えば 今はただの友達
When our eyes meet, right now we're just friends
束ねた長い髪 水玉のシュシュ
Your long hair bundled up with a polka-dot scrunchie
恋の尻尾は 捕まえられない
The tail of love cannot be caught
触れたら消えてく 幻
An illusion that vanishes if touched
ポニーテール ほどかないで
Your ponytail, don't untie it
変わらずに 君は君で 僕は僕で 走るだけ
Without changing, you are you, I am me, just running
ポニーテール ほどかないで
Your ponytail, don't untie it
いつまでも
Forever and ever
はしゃいでいる 君は少女のままで
You keep playing, staying just like a girl
ララララララ...
Lalalalalala...
ココはどこ? 待って言わないで わかってる
Where is this? Don't tell me to wait, I know.
夢に見た熱い蜃気楼なのさ
It's the hot mirage we saw in our dreams.
キミは誰? なんて訊かないよ わかってる
Who are you? I won't ask that, I know.
お互いの願いが呼んだ出会い
An encounter summoned by each other's wishes.
遠ざかるほど輝く一番星
The North Star shining the further away it gets.
いつかそんな恋してみたいんだ
Someday I wanted to try falling in love like that.
もういらないよ胸のブレーキは
I don't need the brakes in my chest anymore.
見つめ合うために生まれた二人になってく
Becoming two people born just to gaze at each other.
Ah!「もしも」は欲しくないのさ「もっと」が好き Angel
Ah! I don't want "what ifs", I want "more", Angel.
翼をただの飾りにはしない
I won't let wings be just decoration.
Ah!「もしも」は欲しくないけど「もっと」が好き Angel
Ah! I don't want "what ifs", but I want "more", Angel.
明日じゃない大事なときは今なんだと気がついて 心の羽ばたきはとまらない
Realizing that when it's crucial, it's not tomorrow, it's right now—the fluttering of my heart won't stop.
あの星は欲しくないのさ もっと好き Angel
That star, I don't want it, I love it even more, Angel.
翼をただの飾りにはしない
I won't let wings be just decoration.
あの星は欲しくないけど もっと好き Angel
That star, I don't want it, but I love it more, Angel.
足りなくない 大事なときは今なんだと気がついて
Realizing that when it's crucial, there's never enough time...
心の羽ばたきはとまらない
The fluttering of my heart won't stop.
僕たちはずっと信じてた
We had always believed in it.
ココはどこ? 待って言わないで わかってる
Where are you? Don't wait and say it, I know.
夢に見た熱い蜃気楼なのさ
It's the hot mirage I dreamed of.
キミはだれ? なんて訊かないよ わかってる
Who are you? I won't ask that, I know.
おたがいの願いが呼んだ出会い
The encounter called by our intertwined wishes.
遠ざかるほど光る一番星
The farthest star shining far away,
いつかそんな恋してみたかった
I wanted to fall in love like that someday.
もういらないよ胸のブレイクは
I don't need heart's brake anymore,
見つめあうために生まれた二人になってく
Becoming two people born to gaze at each other.
Ah! 「もしも」は欲しくないのさ
Ah! "What ifs" are not needed,
「もっと」が好き Angel
I love "more", Angel!
翼をただの飾りにはしない
Don't just use wings as mere decorations.
Ah! 「もしも」は欲しくないけど
Ah! "What ifs" are not needed, but...
「もっと」が好き Angel 明日じゃない
I love "more", Angel! Not tomorrow—
大事なときは今なんだと気がついて
I realized that the important time is right now,
こころの羽ばたきはとまらない
And my heart's flapping won't stop!
Ah! 今宵は一夜限り二度とはない Passion
Ah, tonight is a one-night-only, unrepeatable passion,
燃え尽きるまで踊らなきゃダメさ
We've gotta dance until we burn out!
Ah! 今宵は一夜限り二度とはない Passion
Ah, tonight is a one-night-only, unrepeatable passion,
捕まえたらそのまま強く抱きしめてと叫いた
Once I catch you, I whisper to hold you tight.
愛しい夢はまだ終わらない
My beloved dream is not over yet.
時間はとえられないと知って
I know time can't be stopped,
君と早く会いたかったよ
I wanted to see you so badly.
届けたい言葉が音に溶けていく call angel!
The words I want to send melt into the sound, Call Angel!
Ah! 「もしも」は欲しくないのさ
Ah! "What ifs" are not needed,
「もっと」が好き Angel
I love "more", Angel!
翼をただの飾りにはしない
Don't just use wings as mere decorations.
Ah! 「もしも」は欲しくないけど
Ah! "What ifs" are not needed, but...
「もっと」が好き Angel 明日じゃない
I love "more", Angel! Not tomorrow—
大事なときは今なんだと気がついて
I realized that the important time is right now,
こころの羽ばたきはとまらない
And my heart's flapping won't stop!
あんましものは欲しくないのさ
Even if I don't want to know too much,
もっとが好き Angel
What I really want is more of you, Angel!
翼をただの飾りにはしない
I won't pile up empty words without wings.
あんましものは欲しくないけど
Even if I don't want to know too much,
もっとが好きだけどもっとが好き Angel
What I really want is more of you, Angel!
大事なときは
When it really matters most,
今なんだときは
Right now is the time,
いまなんだときがついて
When our hearts flutter and race,
こころの羽ばたきはとまらない
Our fluttering heartbeats won't stop!
視界全部奪うような 打ち砕くスコールの中でも
Even within a score that captures everything,
きっとさらわれ流されるのは 言言い訳と迷いだけよ
Only my excuses and doubts will wash away.
ぬかるんだ現状に足を奪われて
Stumbling and getting caught in the present,
陰鬱な空気がが喉ふさいででも
Even if heavy air chokes my throat,
この声は絶やさないででしょう
This voice of mine will never cease,
この足は止まらないででしょう
These legs of mine will never stop.
いのちのかぎり どうか全力で射抜いてよ
Shoot through it with all your might for as long as you live!
瞳で私を焼き付けていこう それは約束の進化系
Seer me with your gaze, that's the evolution of a promise.
傷を痛がって投げ出す程度の思いじゃない
It's not enough to just throw away pain,
キミは目撃者だよ yes… unlimited impact
You are the witness, yes... unlimited impact!
強くなって向かい風に 順応したくない本能
Getting stronger to face the headwind,
ふっとさらわれ飛んでいくよ ためらいも臆病さも
Swept away by the wind, hesitation and cowardice alike.
逆境なぐらいで絶望だとか
Adversity is not despair,
マイナス先入観は似合わない
Negative preconceptions don't fit here.
劣勢ならあとは攻めるだけ この夢は揺るがないでしょう
If we're at a disadvantage, we just keep attacking!
ココロのかぎり 今を生きたいよ
With all the strength left in our hearts,
未完成な私で胸を張っていこう
Let's live the present to the fullest.
何があったってスタートをしたなら行くっきゃない
Once we start, we have to keep going!
静かに なれ と 悲しい 嵐 の 中 で
"Quiet," I say, in the sad storm
痛い こころ が 痛む よ
It hurts—my heart is in pain
惨劇 に 慣れ て 苦し さ に 飽き て
Used to tragedies, tired of suffering
先 を 急ぐ 遠い 旅 へ と
I go on a long journey, hurrying forward
閉じ られる 場所
At the confined place
光 で 暴く 未来
The future is revealed by light
そう だ ね … 私 達 は 愛さ れ た 瞬間 を 想い出し て
That's right... When we recall the moment when we were loved,
生き て 行ける
We can go on living
激しく 乱れ た ZONE//ALONE
In the fierce chaos of ZONE//ALONE
「 助け て 」 の 声 に 呼ば れ て
Summoned by your voice calling out, "Save me"
追いかけ て も 追いかけ て も
Even as I chase, even as I chase after you
その 手 が 掴め ない
I can't catch your hand
確かめる 過去 は ZONE//ALONE
The past to be confirmed is ZONE//ALONE
絶望 超え て 探せ ！ 太陽 の 向こう
Overcome your despair—Search beyond the sun!
さらに 渇い て 満たさ れ ぬ 星 墜ち た
Unsatiated when it grew even thirstier, the star fell
欲しい 明日 が 欲しい ね
It wants tomorrow—it wants tomorrow
無力 な 事実 重ねれ ば 真実
The facts are helpless, but when I put them together, they become the truth
夢 を 奪う 者 を 弾く
Blocking those who steal dreams
眩しい 命
Life is brilliant
輝く 為 の 未来
The future will shine
そう だ よ … 私 達 壊れ ちゃ いけない 絶対 に 今 を
That's right... We absolutely mustn't get broken down,
生き て 飛ん で
So live and soar now
言葉 を 亡くし て DOWN//UNKNOWN
Losing my words in DOWN//UNKNOWN
取り戻す 意味 を 知り たい
I want to know the point of recovering them
信じる ほど 信じる ほど
The more I believe, the more I believe,
進め ぬ もどかし さ
The less progress I can make, to my frustration
確かめ て みせ て DOWN//UNKNOWN
Show me that you'll confirm the DOWN//UNKNOWN
凛々しい 希望 を 鳴らし ！ 銀河 の 果て
Make the noble hope resound! To the ends of the Milky Way
優しい 祈り 降り注ぐ
A tender prayer pours down
大事 な 人 の こと を 強く 胸 に 刻ん で
I firmly etch those important to me into my heart
優しく 降り注ぐ の は 愛 だ と 教わっ て みたい
I want to be told that love is what's pouring down tenderly
激しく 乱れ た ZONE//ALONE
In the fierce chaos of ZONE//ALONE
助け て 欲しい と 呼ん だ ね … ？
You called out that you want to be saved, right...?
激しく 乱れ た ZONE//ALONE
In the fierce chaos of ZONE//ALONE
「 助け て 」 の 声 に 呼ば れ て
Summoned by your voice calling out, "Save me"
追いかけ て も 追いかけ て も
Even as I chase, even as I chase after you
その 手 が 掴め ない
I can't catch your hand
確かめる 過去 は ZONE//ALONE
The past to be confirmed is ZONE//ALONE
絶望 超え て 探せ ！ 太陽 の 向こう
Overcome your despair—Search beyond the sun!
銀河 の 果て まで も
And even to the ends of the Milky Way
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl?
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
星を巡るよ 純情
I'll go around the stars, pure emotion.
弱虫 泣き虫 連れて
Taking a coward and crybaby along,
まだ行くんだと思う わたし
I think I'm still going on.
愛する より 求める より
Rather than loving, rather than seeking,
疑うほうがずっとたやすい自分が悔しい
It's much easier to doubt—I regret myself.
痛いよ
It hurts.
味方だけど愛してないとか
Being on your side yet not loving you,
守るけど側にいれないとか
Protecting you yet not being able to stay by your side,
苦い二律背反
A bitter antinomy.
今すぐタッチミー
Touch me right now!
運命ならばつないで
If it's destiny, connect us.
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl?
心 揺らす 言葉 より
Rather than words that shake the heart,
無責任 に 抱い て 限界
Hold irresponsibly and hit the limit.
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or that girl?
心揺らす言葉
Words that shake the heart...
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or perhaps her?
妄想砂漠を着て
Clad in a desert of delusions,
後ろから蹴り上げたら
If I kick up from behind,
飛び出しの恋に溺れた
I drowned in a sudden love.
呼吸だけで精一杯
Just breathing takes all I have,
向かいにきておぼれてるから
As I'm drowning, come meet me.
痛いよ
It hurts.
前向きな嘘
Taking a positive lie
真に受けるのは
At face value
笑ってる声がせめないから
Because the laughing voice doesn't blame me.
未来も手探りでした
The future was also a fumble in the dark.
今すぐ hold me
Hold me right now,
理性なんて押し倒して
Knocking reason aside.
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or perhaps her?
涙まるで役立たず
Tears are totally useless,
星を駆けるよ 純情
Running through the stars with pure emotion.
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or perhaps her?
たったひとつ命を立てに
Putting a single life on the line,
今振りかざす感情
Now brandishing my feelings.
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or perhaps her?
君は誰とキスをする
Who do you kiss?
わたし それとも あの娘
Me, or perhaps her?
たったひとつ命を立てに
Putting a single life on the line,
今振りかざす感傷
Now brandishing my sentiment.
たったひとつ命を立てに
Putting a single life on the line,
今振りかざす感傷
Now brandishing my sentiment.
アイドルはウーニャニャの件
[Song: The Case of the Uunyanya Idol]
ウニャウニャウニャ ウニャウニャウニャ ウニャウニャニャ ウニャウニャウニャウニャウニャウニャ ウニャニャニャオー
Unya unya unya...
昔のアイドルなんてだって
Past idols and all that...
好きゃうんだるわのーさうきゅう
Can't just run away now!
だけど今は逃げられない
Walls have ears, shoji screens have eyes.
壁に耳あり障子に目あり
Spreading in the blink of an eye,
あっという間に拡散しちゃう
Net flamewars erupt.
ネットで炎上
やってられない清純派
This purity act is impossible.
白黒つけずにスルーでごめん
Sorry for sliding through without black and white.
ホントじゃないけど嘘でもない
Not the whole truth, but not a lie either.
とっつかえずで七転八倒
Stumbling around through turmoil.
ウニャウニャウニャ ウニャウニャウニャ ウニャウニャニャ...
Unya unya unya...
あ、私だって知らんぷりだっていつでもよくし...
Ah, acting like I don't know anything...
ツチノコパンダよ味方してー
Tsuchinoko Panda, take my side!
はいっ！
Yes!
サングラスかけ マスクをして
Wearing sunglasses and a mask,
だけど私だと 気づいて
hoping someone will still notice it's me.
プライベートは 自由はダメ
Private life and freedom aren't allowed,
写真もダメと 上から目線
talking down to us, forbidding even photos.
そんな自分が 好きじゃなくなる
I'm starting to dislike myself like this.
裸の王様
A naked king,
なぜか涙が 溢れてる
tears are somehow overflowing.
私は何者 ここはどこなのよ
Who am I? Where is this place?
夢のようで も夢じゃなし
It's like a dream, yet not a dream.
天国みたいで 天国じゃない
It's like heaven, yet not heaven.
ウニャニャウニャニャ ウニャニャニャよ
Woonyanya, woonyanya, woonyanya...
ああ アイドルだって時には捕まるし
Ah, even idols get caught sometimes,
光にいえない 秘密もあるわ
and have secrets we can't tell the light.
ツチノコパンダよ ヘルプミー
Tsuchinoko Panda, help me!
アイドル 女の子
As an idol, as a girl,
動くのも 慣れず
I still can't get used to moving around,
バカになれなくなる
and can no longer act foolish.
私は私 誰ですか
Who am I? Who on earth am I?
ウニャニャウニャニャ ウニャニャニャよ
Woonyanya, woonyanya, woonyanya...
ああ アイドルだって悩んでいるの
Ah, idols have their worries too,
みんなが憧れる 世界じゃない
it's not the world everyone admires.
ツチノコパンダよ 分かるでしょ
Tsuchinoko Panda, you understand, right?
ツチノコパンダよ 見たして
Tsuchinoko Panda, fulfill me!
恋になりたいAQUARIUM
I Want to Fall in Love in AQUARIUM
冷たい風をふう
A cool breeze blows by,
海の上のウェルカム
welcoming us above the sea.
あそびましょ
Let's go play!
ゆらゆらゆれながら 真珠の時計
Swaying gently, a pearl clock ticks away.
きみとわたしを 夢に誘いこむの
It invites you and me into a dream.
水底で騒ぐ さわいで跳ねる 魚たちのパーティ
A party of fish making a fuss and jumping at the seabed!
呼ばれちゃったんだ
We've been invited,
水の中でも 息ができるの
able to breathe even underwater!
お風呂あがりの熱い お茶のせいかな
Must be because of the hot tea after a bath.
真ん中の彼は 気にしなしないって
The guy in the middle says not to worry about it!
魚たちのパーティ 楽しもうか
Shall we enjoy the fish party?
とっても とっても 楽しさはバタバタ
It's so, so wonderfully bustling,
一緒に ブカブカしちゃいぼう
let's float along together.
いつも主役は 私になれ
May I always be the leading lady.
遠くが聞こえる 髪まで
Hearing sounds from afar, even in my hair,
近づきたいな I miss you
I want to get closer... I miss you.
アクアウリウムで 二人が出逢うファンタジー
A fantasy where the two of us meet in the aquarium.
ふいに ときめくの それは恋の魔法
Suddenly my heart races—that's the magic of love.
アクアウリウムで 気づいて
Realize it here in the aquarium,
胸の奥に秘めてた 本当の気持ち
the true feelings hidden deep in my heart.
本当の気持ち
My true feelings,
これから素直になってみよう
from now on, I'll try to be honest.
大好きは隠さない！
I won't hide my love anymore!
だって水の中じゃ 秘密も日常も
Because underwater, secrets and daily life
上から上まで 上手に泳げるね
can all be swum through smoothly from top to bottom.
水深は浅いの？ 水深は深いの？
Is the water shallow? Is the water deep?
魚たちはなんでも 知ってるよ
The fish know everything.
しっかり しっかり 楽しんで
Enjoy it thoroughly, firmly,
最後は一緒に
and in the end, let's be together.
空色カーテン オープン！
Open the sky-blue curtain!
海色ゲート ウェルカム！
Welcome to the ocean gate!
遊びましょう！
Let's play!
ゆらゆら 揺れながら 真珠の時計
Swaying, swaying, the pearl clock
きみとわたしを 夢にさそいこむの
invites you and me into a dream.
水槽で さわぐ さわいで はねる
Making a fuss in the tank, splashing and jumping,
魚たちの パーティー ほどけちゃった
the fish party got untangled!
なんで？ 水の中でも いきができるの？
Why? Can we breathe even underwater?
たぶん さっき飲んだ 熱いお茶のせいかな
Probably because of the hot tea I drank just now.
まあ そんなことは きにしない 気にしないって
Well, let's not worry about details!
魚たちの パーティー たのしみもうか
Fish party, let's enjoy it!
とっても とっても たのしそう
It looks so, so much fun!
(ぷかぷか〜)
(Float-float~)
だったら いっしょに ぷかぷか しちゃえば？
If so, why don't we float together?
いつもと ちがう わたしになれ
Become a different me than usual,
といきが きこえる ぎょりまで
until I can hear your breathing closely.
近づきたいな I miss you...
I want to get closer, I miss you...
アクアリウムで
At the aquarium,
(Yeah!)
ふたりが 出会う ファンタジー
a fantasy where the two of us meet.
ふいに とめくの
Suddenly fluttering,
それは 恋の魔法
that is the magic of love.
(Fantastic love!)
アクアリウムで
At the aquarium,
(Yeah!)
きづいて 胸の奥に 秘めてた
Realize what was hidden deep in my heart.
(Ooh yay!)
本当の 気持ち
My true feelings.
これから 素直になってみよう
From now on, let's be honest!
だいすきよ もうかくさない！
I love you so much, I won't hide it anymore!
(ない！)
(No!)
水深は あさいの？
Is the water shallow?
青春は ふかいの？
Is youth deep?
魚たちは なんでも しってるよ
The fish know everything!
しっかり しっかり たのしんで
Enjoying it thoroughly, thoroughly,
(あわわ〜)
(Bubble-bubble~)
さいごは いっしょに あわわ にのって
in the end, riding the bubbles together!
また あえるね わたしに キス
We'll meet again, kiss me—
しちゃえば？ しちゃいたい？
shall we? Do you want to?
しちゃいな よ！
Just do it!
いま だけって
Only now,
きみ だけって
only you,
I love you!
(I love you!)
マリンブルーなら
If it's marine blue,
(Yeah!)
ふたりは 夢の シンフォニー
the two of us form a dream symphony.
きっと かなえるの
Surely making it come true,
あまい 恋の 奇跡
the sweet miracle of love.
(Fantastic eyes!)
マリンブルーなら
If it's marine blue,
(Yeah!)
はじめて なのに こわくないんだもん
even though it's my first time, I'm not scared!
(Ooh... Yeah!)
ほんとに わたし
Truly myself,
つぎから 大胆になってみよう
from now on, let's be bold!
だいすきよ もうかくさない！
I love you so much, I won't hide it!
(ない！)
(No!)
さそっちゃうんだ wow wo!
Inviting you, wow wo!
アクアリウムで
At the aquarium,
さそっちゃうんだ wow wo!
inviting you, wow wo!
恋になりたい
I want to fall in love
(Fantastic!)
遊びましょう！
Let's play!
ぷかぷか で あわわ で みつめあって いいだいな
Floating, bubbling, gazing at each other, isn't that nice?
だいすき wow wo!
I love you, wow wo!
アクアリウムで
At the aquarium!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
(CHU-LU CHU-LU CHU-LU PA-YA-PA)
(DISCO LADY...)
(DEEP EMOTION...)
SWEETIE DARLIN' 踊りましょう 弾ける BEAUTY LADY
Sweetie Darlin' let's dance, the bursting Beauty Lady,
生まれ変わって甘い夢 そっと彩りたいの
I want to be reborn and softly color the sweet dream.
グラマラスなくちびる ピンク色の艶めくネイル
Glamorous lips and pink shining nails,
ガラスの向こう側に映る素顔 シュールなDays
surreal days reflecting true faces beyond the glass.
キミだけにSO 見せていたい
I want to show you only to you,
心の中瞳の奥 AH 傍にいて欲しいよ
deep within my heart and eyes. Ah, I want you by my side!
月のMIRROR BALL 照らされて
Illuminated by the moon's mirror ball,
MY DARLIN' ねえ ヴィヴィッドな恋しましょ
My Darlin' hey, let's have a vivid love,
はじける SEXY BEAUTY
a bursting Sexy Beauty!
生まれ変わって 甘い夢
Reborn into a sweet dream,
そっと彩る MY LOVE ほら 世界は変わる
softly coloring My Love, see, the world changes!
(CHU-LU CHU-LU CHU-LU PA-YA-PA)
ドラマティックな情熱 褪せない デジャヴ 見続けたくて
Wanting to continue watching the dramatic passion and fadeless deja vu,
カラフルな SWEETY STORY 心深く 刻み込む
engraving the colorful Sweety Story deep in my heart.
小さな闇が 訪れても 恋の呪文 唱えたなら
Even if small darkness visits, if we chant the spell of love,
そう きっと 果てない空 星屑の SHOWER が
yes, surely stardust showers will rain down
降り注ぐ だから HAPPY STATION 目指してゆこう
on the endless sky, so let's aim for the Happy Station!
ギミーギミー あわせて たくさんセント以上の愛
Gimme gimme, match it with over 1000% of love!
揺るぎなく ここにあると 私思ってる
I believe it's unwavering and right here.
CHU-LU CHU-LU CHU-LU PAYA-PA
プログレッシブと コンサバティブな自分
A progressive and conservative self,
キミにありのままを 好きでいて欲しい…と
Wants you to love me just as I am...
願いは DISCO LADY
That's my wish, DISCO LADY.
赤裸々な DEEP EMOTION
Revealing, DEEP EMOTION.
MY DARLIN' もっと一緒に踊りましょう
MY DARLIN', let's dance together more!
SECRET NIGHT 素敵な ラブサングのデコレーション
SECRET NIGHT, a lovely love song's decoration,
2人のハートで AH 奏合わせて
With our two hearts, AH, harmonizing together!
ねえ ビビローなくしましょう
Hey, let's lose our inhibitions,
はじける セクシー 生まれ変わって甘い夢
Bursting, sexy, reborn into a sweet dream,
もっと彩る マラカス ほら 世界は変わる
Coloring it more with maracas, look, the world changes!
CHU-LU CHU-LU CHU-LU PAYA-PA
ヘイ！みこち、５周年 おめでとう！ お祝いに行きまーす！ありがとう！
Hey! Mikochi, happy 5th anniversary! We're here to celebrate! Thank you!
裸足でSummer
Hadashi de Summer
いつもの夏と違うんだ 誰も気付いていないけど
It's different from the usual summer, though nobody's noticed yet.
ざわめく強さがどうか 花の色や鮮やかさとかも
I hope the rustling strength, the flower's colors and vibrancy,
何度も季節は巡って どこかに忘れいていたもの
The seasons have turned over and over, something I left somewhere behind,
誰かを好きになる切なさに 出口を尋ねるの
Asking for the exit to the sorrow of falling in love with someone.
オレンジ色の夕陽の １ピース 最後の一度
One piece of the orange sunset, the very last time,
僕で太陽が似合うのは キミと脱いだスティーブ
What suits the sun is you and me taking off our boots.
裸足になって波打ち際を なぜ一人微笑むの
Why do you smile alone, barefoot at the water's edge?
テーブルの下さりげなく サンダル脱ぎ捨てて
Casually slipping off your sandals under the table,
裸足になってどうするの 少しそのまま どこかへ歩いてゆくよ
What will you do barefoot? Just like that, you start walking somewhere.
なんだって付き合うさ 行動が予測できないよ 人の目に気にせずに気まぐれでそう
I'll go along with anything! Your actions are unpredictable, paying no mind to other people's eyes, so whimsical.
キミにいつも振り回されて 呆れたり疲れたり
Always being pushed around by you, getting fed up or exhausted,
それでもキミに恋をしている 今の距離感が心地いい 普通で楽なんだ
Even so, I'm in love with you. This current distance feels comfortable, so natural and easy.
近くくにいつも大勢いいるよ 男友達 その中のひとりが僕と
There are always lots of guys nearby, male friends, and one of them is me.
悔しいけどしょうがない 告白もしてないし 今の距離感が心地いい 普通で楽なんだ
It's frustrating, but it can't be helped. I haven't confessed either, but this distance feels comfortable and easy.
それなら僕も話になって 一緒にどこでも歩いてゆくよ
In that case, I'll join the conversation too, and walk anywhere together with you.
なんたって付き合うさ 愛おしさが背中を押した 自分の気持ちは隠したまま
Whatever it takes, I'll go with you! The cuteness pushed my back, keeping my own feelings hidden.
そうキミといると 素直になれる 欲しいものは 前より
Yes, being with you makes me honest. What I want is... more than before.
いつもの夏と違うんだ
It's different from the usual summer,
誰も気づいていないけど
though nobody seems to notice.
いつもの夏と違うんだ 君は
It's different from the usual summer, though you
気づいていないけど
don't realize it, but...
歩いている回数も
The number of times we've met,
触れた指の引っ込め方も
and how you pull back your touched fingers...
何度も鏡を見ながら
Looking in the mirror over and over,
寝癖も直してきたこと
fixing your bedhead.
苦しくなるくらい
To the point of becoming painful,
すべてがぎこちない
everything is awkward.
I know...
裸足になってどうするつもり？
What do you plan to do, going barefoot?
そのままどこかへ歩いていくの？
Are you just going to walk off somewhere like that?
ねえ 何をしたいんだ
Hey, what is it you want to do?
行動が予測できないよ
Your actions are so unpredictable.
他人の目気にせず気まぐれで…
Without caring about other people's eyes, on a whim...
そう君にいつも振り回されて
That's how you always push me around,
あきれたり疲れたり
getting exasperated, getting tired.
それでも君に恋をしている
Even so, I'm in love with you.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Couldn't beat her smile, it stirred up all the media,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Secret side, I wanna know it so mysterious.
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even that elusive side, part of her controlled area,
完璧で嘘つきな君は
Complete and perfect, all you say is a lie—
天才的なアイドル様
Dear miss genius idol, unmatched!
今日何食べた？
What did you eat today?
好きな本は？
What book do you love?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
Whenever you go out for fun, tell me, where do you go?
何も食べてないそれは内緒
Haven’t eaten anything, it's a secret, unknown.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Any questions you're facing, always acting so vaguely.
そう淡々と
So unconcerned,
だけど爛々と
although you brightly glow.
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Any seemingly unveiled secrets are as sweet as honey.
あれもないないない
Confusing, why, why, why?
これもないないない
Essential lie, lie, lie.
好きなタイプは？相手は？さあ答えて
So, what is your type of guy? Any partner? Answer this!
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からないからさ」
"I don't have any idea how I could love anyone."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Cannot find out if it's true or it's a lie.
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
Once again, there's somebody who's fallen for the words,
また好きにさせる
Made him lose his head over you.
誰もが目を奪われていく
That emotion melts all hearts, all eyes on you.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
'Cause you are perfect, the most ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
Unrivaled, will not appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
It's the brightest star reborn, yes, indeed.
ああ、その笑顔で愛してるで
Using that smiling face, that I love you again,
誰も彼も虜にしていく
Now, everybody is lured and captivated by you.
その瞳がその言葉が
The pupil that you got, the words you vocalize,
嘘でもそれは完璧なアイ
Even when untrue, it’s your perfected ai.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Right, right, we all know she's very special, yes.
我々はハナからおまけです
We had lost the fight before it started, so impressed.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're serving as support to her grace.
全てがあの子のおかげなわけない
Cannot tell me everything was cause of her,
洒落臭い、妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
Out of line, how can we not feel jealous?
わけがない、これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
It's not a joke in her eyes, so I cannot forgive you.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない自分を許せない
Completely deny imperfect you that I sight, no pardon allowed.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't allow anyone if it's not you, strongest of all.
誰もが信じ崇めてる、まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
That emotion seized all hearts worshiping you, unrivaled idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
There cannot be weaknesses to find,
一番星を宿している
The brightest star is residing in you.
見せちゃダメダメ見せちゃいけない
The gaps and shortcomings, don't show ’em, dammit, dammit.
知られたくないところは見せずに
Parts nobody wants to know should remain hidden.
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
One and only, if it's different, no way, no way.
それこそ本物のアイ
Such a true love, it's the realest ai.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Showing this smile, my own weapon boiling media,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Keeping everything about my secret deep inside.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
I'm in love with you, my career is built on such a lie.
これこそ私なりの愛だ
It's the way I know to show my love, without a doubt.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Running down, my sweat is flowing, cleanest aqua, right?
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
Ruby hidden under my eyelids where it resides.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
I sing and dance around look at me, I'm maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
So, lying surely is the greatest kind of love.
誰かに愛されたことも誰かのこと愛したこともない
I have never been loved by anyone, nor have I loved anyone else.
そんなたちの嘘がいつか本当にになること信じてる
That such lies of mine will become true someday, I trust in it.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Someday, surely, I will have it all in hand, I am such a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのことを
Because I wish to love everybody properly in a life-sized way,
ちゃんとき愛したいから今日も嘘をつく
I shall lie today as well, hoping that one day, these words will come true.
今日も嘘をつくの この言葉が
So today, I lie again, hoping these words...
いつか本当に なる日を願って
will one day become the truth.
それでもまだ 君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
And yet, to you and you alone, I couldn't say it.
ああ、やっと言えた これは絶対嘘じゃない
Ah, I finally said it. This is definitely no lie.
愛してる
I love you.
はーい、ということで、ライブは残すところあと1曲となるんですが！
Alright, so the live is down to just one song left!
ゲストパートの、お二人には、お、務めさせていただいた、あ、務めていただいた、はい！
We'd like to—um, have—wait, who kindly served as our guest—yes!
星街すいせいさんと告知タイムをしたいと思います！
We'd like to hold a notification time with Hoshimachi Suisei-san!
星街すいせいですよ！さくらみこさんの旅はくしゅうねんおめでとうございます！
I'm Hoshimachi Suisei! Congratulations on Sakura Miko-san's 5th anniversary!
ありがとうございます、すいせいさん！私も一番最後に一緒にね、アイドルを歌っていただきまして！
Thank you, Suisei-san! And you sang "Idol" together with me right at the very end!
究極のアイドルね！でも楽しかったですね！
The ultimate idol, right? But it was a lot of fun!
アイドルらしくね！アイドルらしくね！はい！コピタイム！
Idol-like, right? Idol-like, right? Yes! Copy time!
はーい！こみはにゃーん！
Yay! Come-ha-nya-n!
はい、こみはにゃん！はい、こみはにゃん！パワワはー！
Yes, come-ha-nya-n! Yes, come-ha-nya-n! Pow-wa-wa!
にゃにゃーん！にゃにゃーん！あいどるにゃにゃーん！
Nya-nya-n! Nya-nya-n! Idol-nya-nya-n!
私が前でいいんですか？あ、いいんですか？じゃあ前でどうぞ！
Is it okay if I'm in front? Oh, is it okay? Then go ahead in front!
はい、どうぞ！
Yes, go ahead!
え、じゃあ、なんですか？ピースよ！ピース！ピース！
Um, well then, what is it? Peace! Peace! Peace!
あれやって、ちょっと、私乗るわ、そ、そ、そ、あの、何？あれやってよ！
Do that, wait, I'll join in, th-th-th-that, what? Do that!
あれ、手出してよ！
Do that, put your hands out!
あ！ちょこっとすいちゃん！ちょこっとすいちゃん！かわいい！かわいい！
Ah! Chokotto Suichan! Chokotto Suichan! So cute! So cute!
はい、ということでね、皆さんよろしいでしょうか？はい、告知があるということでね！
Alright, so everyone, are you ready? Yes, since there are announcements!
やっていきたいと思います！まずはグッズの告知、こちら！ドン！
Let's get into it! First is the merch announcement, right here! Boom!
さくらみこ5周年記念グッズが出まーーーす！おめでとう！すごい！かわいい！
Sakura Miko's 5th anniversary merchandise is out! Congratulations! Amazing! So cute!
ということで、えーじゃあまず1つ1つね、紹介していこうと思います！まずはこっちな！
So, um, let's introduce them one by one! First is this one!
はい、こちらがですね、5周年記念のパブミラーとなっております！
Yes, this is the 5th anniversary pub mirror!
パブミラーってなんなんですか？
What on earth is a pub mirror?
パブミラーは、あのなんか、鏡にね、こうやってピュッてやってて、キラキラして記念！みたいなの。
A pub mirror is, like, on a mirror, you do a quick polish like this, all sparkly and commemorative!
全然わかりませんでした。
I had no idea at all.
すごい豪華なんです！おるだん先生がみこの水着をデザインしてくれて、とてもかわいい写真となっております！
It's super luxurious! Orudan-sensei designed Miko's swimsuit, making it a super cute photo!
じゃあまあね、じゃあまあね、じゃあまあ、おめでとう！はい、こちらぜひ買ってくだしゃい！
Well then, well then, well, congratulations! Yes, please definitely buy this!
そして、なんとこちらドン！
And what's more, here is—boom!
はい、マグチのぬいぐるみが出るんですね！ついにこのように具現化したんですね！
Yes, a Maguchi plushie is coming out! It finally materialized like this!
具現化しました！しかもあのマシュマロみでむにゅもにゅって感じでね、もにゅもにゅぶちぶちって感じで、とっても可愛く出来上がってるので！
It materialized! Plus, it feels all squishy and marshmallow-like, very cute and plumply finished!
すいちゃんもねぬいぐるみ好きだからね！ペアでね、是非買ってくだしゃい！出るか分かりませんが！
Suichan also likes plushies, right! As a pair, definitely buy them! Though I don't know if [Suichan] will!
はいそしてこちらドン！ひっかける見守り35Pマスコットといまして！
Yes, and here—boom! It's called the "Hanging Watching 35P Mascot"!
みこぴー？そう、これみこぴーのちっちゃいのあるね！これがデスクとかのちょこんって乗る感じになっております！
Miko-p? Yes, this is a little Miko-p! It's made to sit right on your desk or somewhere cute like that.
なるほど！かわいい！これホロライブで流行りじゃないかな？ぜひ買ってくだしゃい！
I see! Cute! Isn't this trending in Hololive right now? Please definitely buy it!
そしてなんとなんと！こちらドドン！
And what, oh what! Here—dodoom!
初のEP「heart♡connect」でます！
The very first EP "heart♡connect" is coming out!
わあ！ついにCDが出るよすいちゃん！わあ、すごいでしょう！
Wow! A CD is finally coming out, Suichan! Wow, isn't that amazing?
おめでとうございます！すごいですね！何曲ですか？何曲？
Congratulations! That's amazing! How many songs? How many tracks?
こちらはですね、7曲！なんと「ラッキーセブン」です！ぜひとも買ってくだしゃい！買って！
This is, 7 tracks! Fittingly "Lucky Seven"! Please definitely buy it! Buy it!
こちらね、あのGuchico先生に描き下ろしていただいたジャケットとなっておりまして、めちゃくちゃね夏の感じでかわいいし！
This jacket was newly illustrated by Guchico-sensei, giving it such a summery and cute vibe!
あの帽子にね、3と5って書いてあるの！おーね！いいですね！みこさんらしいですね！
On that hat, it says 3 and 5! Oh, nice! That's very Miko-san!
そうとってもアイドルらしい、アイドルのCDとなっております！よろしくお願いします！
Yes, it's a very idol-like idol CD! Thank you very much!
そしてこちら活動5周年記念フルセット特典として、箱押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りおるだん先生描き下ろしアナザージャケットカードがついてきまーーす！
And as a 5-and-anniversary full set bonus, a box-pressed replicated signed & message-included another jacket card illustrated by Orudan-sensei comes with it!
うわーーすごいですね！
Whoa, that's amazing!
フルセット購入特典のCDにすっと差し込める形となっておりまして、
"It's designed to slip right into the full set bonus CD,"
もうね、CDはね、あのカードの中にもいろんな特典がございまして、ま動画のやつとか? いろいろあるんでね!
"And you know, the CD itself has all sorts of special bonuses inside the card, like video stuff and all sorts of things!"
これCD買わないとね、2枚とか分からないよね。
"If you don't buy the CD, you won't know about getting 2 or more."
そう、2枚とか3枚とかね、さ、飾ってくれたらさ、いいよね!
"Right, if you display two or three of them, wouldn't that be nice!"
っていうことで出しております。
"That's why we're releasing it."
はい、ぜひ皆さん、あの単品でもね、お買い求めください。ください。
"Yes, everyone, please consider purchasing them individually as well."
そして、なんと! あの数量限定も出ます。
"And what's more! There will also be a limited quantity version."
数量限定は直筆メッセージが付きます! ニィ〜とかね。ウホッ! とかさ。
"The limited quantity version comes with a handwritten message! Like 'Nii~' or 'Uho!' and stuff."
何枚書くんですか? いっぱい! いっぱい! です。
"How many are you writing? Lots! Lots of them!"
今回はなんと一杯書きますのでね、皆さん是非この後発売なのでダッシュしてくださいね! よろしくお願いいたします!
"This time I'll be writing so many, so everyone please make a dash for it once it goes on sale! Thank you very much!"
そして、え、このあとアルバムに収録されているさくらが手掛けてくれたハムさん作曲の新曲を初お披露目します!
"And, um, next we will premiere a new song composed by Hamu-san, penned by Sakura, included in the album!"
なんと! お披露目!
"And it's a premiere!"
そしてなんと歌詞も、なんか初めて作詞、頑張りました。
"And what's more, for the lyrics, I tried writing them for the very first time, I worked hard."
なんと! あの巫女さんが? はい、まあハム先生にもね、大丈夫ですか?
"Really! Miko-san did? Yes, well, I asked Hamu-sensei too, 'Is this okay?'"
うん、あ、聞いたね。あちあち! あちいね、あちいね。
"Yeah, I heard about it. Hot hot! It's hot, it's hot."
あちあちあちちみたいな。
"Like 'hot, hot, hot, hot, hot'."
本当にね、巫女ピに対する、活動に対する、もうこれまでの一色のいろんなのを、あの、歌に込めた曲となっておりますので、ぜひ聞いてください。
"Truly, it's a song filled with all sorts of feelings regarding my activities and Mikop, so please give it a listen."
私も少し歌っておりますので、ご注目ください。
"I'm also singing a little bit in it, so please look forward to that."
そう、手伝っていただきましたと。はい。
"That's right, she helped me out. Yes."
はい、ということで、それでは着替えてこようと思います。はい。
"Yes, with that said, we're going to go change clothes. Yes."
それじゃあ行きますよ。失礼いたします。それじゃ、せーの、ばいばーい!
"Well then, let's go. Excuse us. Ready, set, bye-bye!"
アワーツリー 作詞:さくらみこ 作曲・編曲:ハム
[Song: Our Tree / Lyrics: Sakura Miko / Music & Arrangement: Hamu]
ねぇ 思い出したんだ そっと涙した日を
"Hey, I remembered the day I quietly shed tears."
さぁ 数えてみようか これまで起こした奇跡を
"Now, let's count the miracles we've made so far."
ひとつ とまらない足で ふたつ こえていく夢も
"One: with unstoppable feet, Two: dreams we continue to surpass,"
みっつ つながる絆は 君とひろげてきたんだよ
"Three: the bonds that connect, I've expanded them together with you."
何度でも咲くように 続いてくこの物語“ストーリー”
"So they can bloom again and again, this continuing story..."
まだ見たことのない 景色を探しにゆこう
"Let's go search for scenery we haven't seen yet."
花ひとつずつが小さくても ほら 支え合えたら桜になれるよ
"Even if each flower is small, look, if we support each other, we can become cherry blossoms."
ぼくらが繋いだ大きな木は まだ これからも春風に乗って伸びてくのさ
"The big tree we connected together will still continue to grow on the spring breeze."
ひとつ 涙こぼれたら
"One: if a tear spills,"
ふたつ 両手を叩いて みっつ 数えて始めよう
"Two: clap both hands, Three: let's count and begin."
君といれば大丈夫 弱音と本音で泣いたり
"As long as I'm with you, I'll be fine—whether crying from weakness or true feelings,"
諦めかけた分岐“ルート”も 振り返って笑うように ずっと強くなれたんだ
"Even the branch 'route' I almost gave up on, I can look back and smile, I've grown so much stronger."
枝ひとつずつじゃくじけそうでも ほら 支え合えたら大樹になれるよ
"Even if each branch feels like it might break, look, if we support each other, we can become a giant tree."
手と手を合わせた形は花びら この気持ち言葉すら越えて届けるのさ
"The shape of hands put together is a flower petal; I'll deliver these feelings, transcending even words."
冴えない私を好きになってくれたこと
"That you came to love dull old me,"
これからも後悔なんてさせないよ 見ててね
"I won't make you regret it from now on either, just watch me."
意を張ってた頃よりも 強く大きくなったでしょう?
"Stronger and bigger than when I was stubborn, right?"
もっと君を支える側になりたいから
"Because I want to become someone who supports you even more."
空に願う星
Stars wished upon the sky,
涙をあずけて
entrusting my tears...
そろそろぼくも
It's almost time for me too
一歩踏みこむよ
to take a step forward.
ぼくらが育てた大きな木は
The large tree we raised together,
ほら
look—
こんなにも陽だまりのような場所になったよ
it has become such a warm, sunny place.
La La La...
ねぇ 見せてくれたよね
Hey, you showed it to me, didn't you?
こんなに素敵な未来
Such a wonderful future.
さあ まだまだ続くよ
Now, it's still going to continue!
これからもずっとありがとう
Thank you, always and forever.